Jordan Atanasov

Being a developer is not a profession, it's a lifestyle of ever-growing desire to learn. In my almost 10 years of experience in the IT world, I have done everything in my power to teach myself how to develop in the working place and at a point - help others to grow.

I have experienced the whole stack of a software project. From the database layers, through the back end and business logics, passing through the front-end handlings of data and arriving at the pretty UI designs.

As a regional dev lead, I got a taste of the complicated craft of communicating with people. I am still learning how to help a colleague reach their full capacity as a professional and get the most satisfaction of the work atmosphere.

PERSONAL INFORMATION

Nationality: Bulgarian

Date of birth: 4 July 1989

Mobile: +359 887 37 59 17 e-mail:

jiatanasov@gmail.com

Work experience

Sr. It Consultant

Duration: September 2020 - Present

Organization: vmware, Official Website

Main Responsibilities: Integrating VMware cloud infrastructures into various client-

based environments.

Creating new solutions, meeting user requirements and technology needs.

Taking part in estimation and onboarding phase of new projects. Defining Level of Effort, preparing design and execution processes and documentation.

Leading communication with clients. Mentoring and onboarding fellow team members. Conducting interviews.

Technologies: React, TypeScript/JavaScript, Python, Kubernetes, vmware vRealize

Regional Dev Lead / Senior Developer

Duration: October 2017 – August 2020

Organization: Spark Vision AB, Official Website

Main Responsibilities: Technical lead for newly established development team in Bulgaria. Recruit new members and create the Bulgarian branch office. Support and mentor junior members of the team. Work for external clients as well as internal products of the company.

Technologies: .NET Core, WPF, Angular, React, JavaScript, HTML 5

Outsourcing .NET developer / IT Consultant

Duration: September 2013 – September 2017

Organization: Bulpros Consulting, Official Website

Project: Westernacher Consulting

o Role: WPF developer

- o Project goal: Develop add ins for MS Office as part of software package for the notary offices in Baden-Baden region, Germany
- o Technologies: C#, WPF, Windows Forms, XAML, GitHub, Jira, Word Open Office, Mongo DB

Project: Bulpros Consulting Website

o Role: Project Team Lead

Main responsibilities: Head up a team to renovate the company's website. Mentor junior members and take responsibility of official set up and deployment of the project. o Technologies: MS SQL Server, C#, ASP .NET MVC 5, HTML 5, Umbraco CMS, jQuery, CSS, TFS, Azure

Project: KPMG

 Role: Team Lead on site in Berlin. o Project goal: Develop internal system for Siemens. o Technologies: MS SQL Server, C#, ASP .NET MVC 5, HTML 5, Kendo UI, jQuery, CSS, TFS

Project: *Effortel*

o Role: Full stack developer

- o Project goal: Develop a client management system for mobile operators in Italy and Belgium, containing a website and a middle layer, which communicates with the satellite endpoints from the satellite provider.
- o Technologies: MS SQL Server, C#, ASP .NET MVC 5, HTML 5, Kendo UI, jQuery, CSS, TFS

Software developer

Duration: June 2011 – September 2013

Organization: Commetric, Official Website

Main Responsibilities: Create various desktop applications. Develop new features to

custom Media Analysis CRM of the company.

Junior .NET developer

Duration: December 2010 – June 2011

Organization: CNSYS, Official Website

Project: Ministry of Interior Affairs of Bulgaria Customer Management System

Main Responsibilities: Take part in full stack development of system. Fix Bugs.

Education and training

MCTS at Microsoft

Bachelor of Informatics at University of Sofia "Saint Kliment Ohridski"

Secondary education: Mathematics, French and Physics at High school of

Mathematics "Geo Milev", Pleven

Technical skills and competences

<u>Frameworks:</u> <u>Languages:</u> <u>Database competence:</u>

.Net MVC C# MS SQL Server

React Java Cassandra
Window Phone (basic) JavaScript Mongo DB

AngularJS Python(basic)

WPF XAML
WWF HTML
Django CSS